{"categories":[{"name":"Bullying","questions":[{"questionText":"You are in the middle of a chat session and someone says something mean. Should you:","postQuestionText":"Don\u0027t respond and tell an adult.","answers":[{"text":"Say something mean back","correct":false},{"text":"Ask them to apologise","correct":false},{"text":"Don\u0027t respond and tell an adult","correct":true},{"text":"None of the above","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What are some of the risks of playing online games?","postQuestionText":"All of the above.","answers":[{"text":"You may be bullied during an online game","correct":false},{"text":"You may be scammed into giving up in-game items or have your account hacked","correct":false},{"text":"You may encounter someone who deliberately tries to ruin the game for other players (griefer)","correct":false},{"text":"All of the above","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"What is an online troll?","postQuestionText":"Someone who deliberately tries to sabotage your game or upset you.","answers":[{"text":"A character from Lord of the Rings","correct":false},{"text":"A mythical character","correct":false},{"text":"Someone who deliberately tries to sabotage your game or upset you","correct":true},{"text":"A glitch in your computer","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"While you are playing a game online you see the chat being particularly toxic. What is the best course of action?","postQuestionText":"Both C and D are correct. In some cases D is not an available option, therefore the next best thing is to let the toxicity pass. Some games even offer an option to hide the chat.","answers":[{"text":"Engage with other users and try to stop it","correct":false},{"text":"It\u0027s funny take part of the conversation","correct":false},{"text":"Ignore it will pass","correct":true},{"text":"Report the users","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"In which of these virtual enviroments do you think that young people are most likely to be harrassed?","postQuestionText":"Harassment or bullying is most common via social media, although bullying happens in all of these online environments.","answers":[{"text":"Via text","correct":false},{"text":"Via social media","correct":true},{"text":"Via email","correct":false},{"text":"Via online games","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Offensive name-calling is the most common form of online harrassment. In which of these virtual environments do you think it is most common?","postQuestionText":"Online gaming and online forum/discussion site are the most common places where offensive namecalling is likely to be used.","answers":[{"text":"Via text messages","correct":false},{"text":"Via social media","correct":false},{"text":"Online gaming","correct":true},{"text":"Online forum/discussion site","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Do you think that males or females are more likely to be victims of online bullying and more likely to receive physical threats?","postQuestionText":"Males are more likely to be targeted for online bullying and more likely to receive physical threats.","answers":[{"text":"Males","correct":true},{"text":"Females","correct":false},{"text":"Equal","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Do you think that males or females are more likely to be victims of sexual harassment and/or sustained (or prolonged) forms of harassment?","postQuestionText":"Females are more likely to be victims of sexual harassment and/or sustained (or prolonged) forms of harassment.","answers":[{"text":"Males","correct":false},{"text":"Females","correct":true},{"text":"Equal","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Which age group do you think is most likely to become potential victims of online bullying?","postQuestionText":"Research shows that 18-29 year olds are more likely to be victims of online harassment.","answers":[{"text":"18-29","correct":true},{"text":"30-45","correct":false},{"text":"46-60","correct":false},{"text":"61\u002B","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Offensive name calling, purposeful embarrassment stalking and physical threats are all types of what?","postQuestionText":"Harassment or cyber bullying","answers":[{"text":"Friendly banter","correct":false},{"text":"Harassment or cyber bullying","correct":true},{"text":"Gaming tactics","correct":false},{"text":"Methods for making friends","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What proportion of young people have been subjected to some form of online harassment or cyber bullying?","postQuestionText":"65%","answers":[{"text":"12%","correct":false},{"text":"27%","correct":false},{"text":"48%","correct":false},{"text":"65%","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"For which of these reasons are young people most likely to be targeted for cyber bullying?","postQuestionText":"The answer is A) thier ethnicity at 54%, closely followed by C) their sexual identity at 50%","answers":[{"text":"Their ethnicity","correct":true},{"text":"Their political affiliation","correct":false},{"text":"Their sexual identity","correct":true},{"text":"Their gender","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Cyber bullying has been reported to affect school work, mental health and feelings of social connectedness. What could you advise someone who is a victim of cyber bullying to do?","postQuestionText":"Any of these are all good tactics for dealing with cyber bullies. They gain most of their strength from thinking the victim is not going to seek help.","answers":[{"text":"Engage with other users and try to stop it","correct":false},{"text":"Speak to an adult about it","correct":false},{"text":"Report the users","correct":false},{"text":"Any of the above","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"If you are subjected to cyber bullying how can you evidence what is happening when reporting the incident?","postQuestionText":"Document all activity. The more evidence you can collect, the stronger your case will be.","answers":[{"text":"Keep a diary","correct":false},{"text":"Take screenshots of the behaviour","correct":false},{"text":"Tell a friend","correct":false},{"text":"Document all activity","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"You receive an email from someone called \u0027cyberstalker@outlook.com\u0027 which says: \u0027I\u0027m watching you\u0027. What should you do?","postQuestionText":"Speaking to an adult or reporting it are the best options. You can report any suspicious email via report@phishing.gov.uk and they will investigate.","answers":[{"text":"Reply to the email, telling them to stop emailing you","correct":false},{"text":"Speak to an adult/administrator about it","correct":true},{"text":"Report the email addresss to the National Cyber Security Centre (NCSC)","correct":true},{"text":"Delete and ignore it","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Why should you report unacceptable behaviour on social media platforms?","postQuestionText":"To make the platform aware of the behaviour so they can take action.","answers":[{"text":"To make the platform aware of the behaviour so they can take action","correct":true},{"text":"To embarrass the person","correct":false},{"text":"Because you don\u0027t enjoy their content","correct":false},{"text":"Because you don\u0027t like them","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"If you report behaviour on social media platforms, will the person who holds the account find out that you reported them without you being asked first?","postQuestionText":"The social media platform will never divulge your personal details without first checking with you.","answers":[{"text":"Always","correct":false},{"text":"Never","correct":true},{"text":"Unlikely","correct":false},{"text":"Sometimes","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Is it ever acceptable to post as or message someone pretending to be someone else as a joke?","postQuestionText":"It is never acceptable to share something in somebody else\u0027s name, as you do not know what the repercussions may be for them and/or for yourself.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, if they did it to me first","correct":false},{"text":"No, it is never acceptable","correct":true},{"text":"Yes, if you think they will find it funny","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, they have left their account logged in","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Is it ever acceptable to create a fake profile for someone you know as a prank?","postQuestionText":"IT IS ABSOLUTELY NEVER ACCEPTABLE TO MAKE A FAKE PROFILE FOR SOMEONE ELSE.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, if I do not like them","correct":false},{"text":"No, it is never acceptable","correct":true},{"text":"Yes, if you think they will find it funny","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, if they never find out","correct":false}]}]},{"name":"Information","questions":[{"questionText":"When making an in-game purchase for currency or items, the gaming site or app may ask for what information?","postQuestionText":"All of the above. Gaming sites may keep this information, it is up to you to ensure that your details are correct and if you want them deleted, you need to request this.","answers":[{"text":"Name and address","correct":false},{"text":"Payment card details","correct":false},{"text":"Date of birth","correct":false},{"text":"All of the above","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"True or false: If I delete my online posts they can never be seen again","postQuestionText":"False. Posting is permanent. Many people think that deleting something online means removing it from the internet forever. This is not true. After posting something online, anyone can save, download and re-use it! Just think about all the recent scandals around the uncovering of old, inappropriate tweets by a host of now infamous celebrities!","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Is it okay to share personal information online? ","postQuestionText":"Never reveal personal information, be wary of who is asking for it and tell a parent or teacher. ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, it\u2019s fun to share information","correct":false},{"text":"Only if the person asking appears friendly","correct":false},{"text":"Never reveal personal information, be wary of who is asking for it and tell a parent or teacher.","correct":true},{"text":"Yes, if the person shares their personal information with me","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"You are visiting a site from a company or organization that you\u2019ve never heard of before. Is it okay to enter your name and phone number to enter a contest?","postQuestionText":"No, it is never okay to share your personal details over the internet, unless it is a trusted source.","answers":[{"text":"No, it is never okay to share your personal details over the internet, unless it is a trusted source","correct":true},{"text":"Only if the website is pretty and inviting","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, it\u0027s only a name and number","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, if they promise to keep it safe","correct":false}]},{"questionText":" What kind of photos are okay to post online?","postQuestionText":"Only photos you woud be happy for anybody in the world to see.","answers":[{"text":"No photos whatsoever","correct":false},{"text":"Only if you look nice","correct":false},{"text":"Everything and anything","correct":false},{"text":"Only photos you woud be happy for anybody in the world to see","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"If you\u2019re under 18 and signing up to the website of a new game and the form asks for the following details: full name, email address, home address, telephone number. What do you do?","postQuestionText":"Check the webpage for further details about why they need the information and ask an adult for permission.","answers":[{"text":"Enter your details with no hesitation","correct":false},{"text":"Check the webpage for further details about why they need the information and ask an adult for permission","correct":true},{"text":"Enter somebody else\u0027s details to ward off potential hackers","correct":false},{"text":"Leave the website immediately","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Many apps, websites and games let you use your card to buy items. What is the best approach to protect yourself from your card being use without your permission?","postQuestionText":"Never save your payment information and enter your payment information on every transaction. Saving your payment information may allow others using your device to make payments without needing to login.","answers":[{"text":"Save your payment detail on the website. It says it\u0027s secure","correct":false},{"text":"Use external payment methods such as paypal","correct":false},{"text":"Never save your payment information and enter your payment information on every transaction","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"When making a transaction on ebay or other sites some people may ask to complete the payment outside the site, by offering a lower price. Should you do this?","postQuestionText":"Ebay and other sites take a percentage of the transaction, buying outsite the website may save some money. However, doing so you will lose your buyer protection and if anything goes wrong you won\u0027t be able to recover your money.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, if it will save you some money","correct":false},{"text":"No, you will lose your buyers protection, and if anything goes wrong, you won\u0027t be able to recover your money","correct":true},{"text":"It depends on how good of a deal they\u0027re offering you","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, if they seem like a nice person","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"When you discover a payment was made from a website and it wasn\u0027t you. What should you do?","postQuestionText":"Call the bank to block your card and change the passwords of your accounts if they share the same passwords.","answers":[{"text":"Call the bank to block your card and change the passwords of your accounts if they share the same passwords","correct":true},{"text":"Call first your family and friends to inform them someone is using your card","correct":false},{"text":"Wait before taking action as the money has already been lost","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"When is it okay to save payment information on a device that a child has unsupervised access to?","postQuestionText":"Never, as they might not connect the action of browsing and buying with using real money as it all happens automatically. It\u0027s even more true when saving payment information in games, as they might think it is part of the game.","answers":[{"text":"Never, they may make purchases by mistake not realizing that the money is real","correct":true},{"text":"Always, I trust the children in my life","correct":false},{"text":"Sometimes, if it is password protected","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Often sites offer free trials. When joining these free trials, what should you be careful about?","postQuestionText":"To cancel your trial before the end, as they might start to take money without you noticing.","answers":[{"text":"Getting as much use out of the site as possible before the free trial ends","correct":false},{"text":"Not to use the site too much, so I won\u0027t miss it when the trial ends","correct":false},{"text":"To cancel your trial before the end, as they might start to take money without you noticing","correct":true},{"text":"That my friends join so we can all use the free trial","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"How do you know what you should share online?","postQuestionText":"A good rule of thumb is to never share anything online that you wouldn\u2019t be happy to publish on the front page of a newspaper.","answers":[{"text":"Ask your best friend for their opinion","correct":false},{"text":"A good rule of thumb is to never share anything online that you wouldn\u2019t be happy to publish on the front page of a newspaper","correct":true},{"text":"If it\u0027s what everyone else is sharing","correct":false},{"text":"Whatever feels right in the moment","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What is smishing?","postQuestionText":"Smishing is when someone tries to trick you into giving them your private information or following a link to an unsafe website via a text or SMS message that is disguised to appear genuine.","answers":[{"text":"A malicious text message disguised to appear genuine","correct":true},{"text":"A way of ending your online relationship","correct":false},{"text":"A form of online trolling","correct":false},{"text":"A viral TikTok trend","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"You are online and get a message from your internet service provider asking for your password to fix something on your account. Should you give it to them?","postQuestionText":"No, your passwords should never be shared, even for the purpose of computer repair.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, if you trust them","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, always","correct":false},{"text":"No, never","correct":true},{"text":"Yes, if they know your provider","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"You should use the same passwords for all of your accounts so you can easily remember them?","postQuestionText":"No, you should use different passwords for different accounts. This is because if someone uncovers one of your passwords, they will have the key to other account you use that password for.","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":false},{"text":"No","correct":true},{"text":"It depends","correct":false},{"text":"Sometimes","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"You are having trouble doing an activity on a safe site you use at school, when your friend offers to help but needs your password. Should you give your password to them?","postQuestionText":"No, you must always keep your password a secret. NEVER give it to anyone else.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, it does not matter who has my password for a safe website","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, if they can fix the problem","correct":false},{"text":"Possibly, if they promise not to share it with anyone else","correct":false},{"text":"No, you must always keep your password a secret","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"What is a \u0027digital footprint\u0027?","postQuestionText":"A digital footprint is a trace of all your online activities. A digital footprint can help to discover where every piece of data or information originated from and who wrote/posted it.","answers":[{"text":"Posting photos of your feet","correct":false},{"text":"A record of where you have agreed to share your information online","correct":false},{"text":"Your browser history","correct":false},{"text":"A digital trace of all your online activities","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Is it true that once you review your privacy settings on a website, you never need to think about them again?","postQuestionText":"False. Websites and services are constantly changing and updating their privacy setting options, and adding new and useful tools. ","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"On Facebook, you can inform them of your preferences for what happens to your profile if you die, this is called\u2026.","postQuestionText":"Memorialisation options can be found in your settings.","answers":[{"text":"Immortalisation","correct":false},{"text":"Memorialisation","correct":true},{"text":"Rememberisation","correct":false},{"text":"Reinvention","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Some social networking platforms now provide you with an opportunity to set your preferences for what happens to you profile when you pass away, which of these platforms offer this service?","postQuestionText":"None of the above.","answers":[{"text":"LinkedIn","correct":false},{"text":"Twitter","correct":false},{"text":"Instagram","correct":false},{"text":"Google","correct":false},{"text":"None of the above","correct":true},{"text":"None of the above","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"How can you update your privacy information on Facebook?","postQuestionText":"Go to Settings; on most social media platforms, your security and privacy information and options can be found in your settings.","answers":[{"text":"Go to edit profile","correct":false},{"text":"Message Mark Zuckerberg directly","correct":false},{"text":"In your about section","correct":false},{"text":"Go to settings","correct":true}]}]},{"name":"Privacy","questions":[{"questionText":"You discover that a business has details about you that are not correct, what should you do?","postQuestionText":"Contact the company and ask them to correct your information. It is important that businesses hold your correct information, particularly financial, because this can affect your credit score and future financial applications. GDPR principle 4: accuracy, requires organisation to keep their information up to date and correct.","answers":[{"text":"Ignore it, it doesn\u0027t really matter","correct":false},{"text":"Complain, they should know better","correct":false},{"text":"Panic and tell your friends","correct":false},{"text":"Contact the company and ask them to correct your information","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Most websites use cookies to track users and their preferences. Which of these are categories of cookie?","postQuestionText":"Notice only: informs visitors that cookies are deployed but does not allow users to set preferences\nNotice \u0026 Opt-Out: informs and allows opt out, may include an \u2018opt-out of all\u2019 option\nNotice \u0026 Opt-In: informs and asks users to opt-in, before cookies are used may include granular \u2018opt-in\u2019 to some (rarely all) cookies","answers":[{"text":"Notice only, Notice \u0026 Opt-Out, Notice \u0026 Opt-In","correct":true},{"text":"Jaffa Cakes \u0026 Shortbread","correct":false},{"text":"Oreo \u0026 Maryland","correct":false},{"text":"No Notice, Record Everything and Select Choices","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What percentage of opt-in cookie consent banners on websites ignore users\u2019 choices?","postQuestionText":"55%","answers":[{"text":"0%","correct":false},{"text":"28%","correct":false},{"text":"55%","correct":true},{"text":"62%","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Cookies are used by many websites to help improve the user experience and collect information about the users who visit the site. There are different types of cookies, which of the following is NOT a type of cookie?","postQuestionText":"Splash is not a type of cookie","answers":[{"text":"Local Storage","correct":false},{"text":"First Party","correct":false},{"text":"Third Party","correct":false},{"text":"Splash","correct":true},{"text":"Session","correct":false},{"text":"Session","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Which of the following do you need to look for to know a website is secure?","postQuestionText":"A padlock, which can be found at the beginning of the website address in front of the URL","answers":[{"text":"A shield","correct":false},{"text":"A padlock","correct":true},{"text":"A star","correct":false},{"text":"A house","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"How many passwords should you have to access your online accounts?","postQuestionText":"A unique password for each account.","answers":[{"text":"One \u2013 so I can remember it","correct":false},{"text":"Two \u2013 one for important accounts and one for others","correct":false},{"text":"Five or six \u2013 alternating between them","correct":false},{"text":"A unique password for each account","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"How do you know if your accounts have been hacked or accessed?","postQuestionText":"You might not always know if someone has your details, so it is a good idea to regulary change your passwords and use two factor authentication where possible.","answers":[{"text":"You notice changes to your profiles","correct":false},{"text":"You get unusual emails","correct":false},{"text":"You notice spending on your accounts","correct":false},{"text":"You might not know if someone has your details or if you have been hacked","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"How does two-factor authentication protect your accounts?","postQuestionText":"It adds an additional layer of security to your online accounts and helps check that the person knows the password and has a linked device","answers":[{"text":"It makes it more of an effort to get access so hackers give up","correct":false},{"text":"Bots and computers can\u2019t hack them","correct":false},{"text":"It adds an additional layer of security to your online accounts","correct":true},{"text":"It doesn\u2019t, companies just want my mobile number to send me marketing","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What proportion of hacking activities start because of stolen or weak passwords?","postQuestionText":"81%","answers":[{"text":"20%","correct":false},{"text":"44%","correct":false},{"text":"62%","correct":false},{"text":"81%","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Will installing a virus checker on my machine keep my PC safe?","postQuestionText":"Just installing a program will help for a little while, but new viruses are spawning all the time so these need updating frequently. The best form of protection is that you only access trustworthy websites and programs.","answers":[{"text":"It will not help at all","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, it will keep me safe no matter what","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, I will be completely safe as long as I keep it updated","correct":false},{"text":"It can help in the short term","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"You\u2019ve gone on a gaming website and it asks you to download some software before you play. What should you do?","postQuestionText":"Stop and think: find out more about any game before downloading anything. It is a good idea to try and find out if the software has come from a trusted source.","answers":[{"text":"Stop and think","correct":true},{"text":"Click the link if someone has recommended it to you","correct":false},{"text":"No, it is never okay","correct":false},{"text":"Download it and find out","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Does setting up parental control on your router or computer protect everyone from accessing undesired websites?","postQuestionText":"It depends on the provider and settings. Every provider will have different ways to control what you can access online.","answers":[{"text":"It will block all websites","correct":false},{"text":"It will block all over 18 websites","correct":false},{"text":"It will not have any effect","correct":false},{"text":"It depends on the provider and settings","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Where can the best parental control options be found?","postQuestionText":"Your router can cover all devices connected to it, while a browser can only offer safety only within itself","answers":[{"text":"Internet provider","correct":false},{"text":"Router","correct":true},{"text":"Browser","correct":false},{"text":"Mum\u0027s phone","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Can setting up parental control on your router offer you protection on all devices in the house?","postQuestionText":"It depends on whether they are connected to that router, if somebody uses data from their smartphone they can circumvent the security measures","answers":[{"text":"Yes, always","correct":false},{"text":"No, never","correct":false},{"text":"It depends","correct":true},{"text":"Not if you are in the garden","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"If you lend your computer to someone else, what is the best way to make sure they do not install unwanted programs, willingly or not?","postQuestionText":"By limiting what they can do on the computer and ensuring they are not given full administrator rights","answers":[{"text":"Limiting what they can do on it","correct":true},{"text":"Supervise them the entire time","correct":false},{"text":"I trust them","correct":false},{"text":"Tell them to be careful","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"True or false: my friends online cannot use my data in a way that I have not agreed to because GDPR will protect me.","postQuestionText":"False: the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) only protects you if it is an organisation that has done something with your data, not if it is your friend or colleague.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Does The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) protect you so that no-one can use your data unless you have agreed to it?","postQuestionText":"There is no guarantee that companies will follow the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)","answers":[{"text":"GDPR will always protect me","correct":false},{"text":"GDPR will not protect me","correct":false},{"text":"GDPR will partially protect me","correct":true},{"text":"I\u0027m not worried about my data","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"How many principles are there in the GDPR?","postQuestionText":"There are 7 principles: \n1. Lawfulness, fairness and transparency\n2. Purpose limitations\n3. Data minimisation\n4. Accuracy\n5. Storage Limitation\n6. Integrity and confidentiality\n7. Accountability","answers":[{"text":"5","correct":false},{"text":"6","correct":false},{"text":"7","correct":true},{"text":"8","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"The GDPR principle of \u0022lawfulness, fairness and transparency\u0022 means what?","postQuestionText":"Lawful: they must inform you under which legal grounds they are using your data.\nFair: they must use \u0026 process the data fairly with your interest in mind. \nTransparency: they must inform you how they will use your information","answers":[{"text":"They must inform you under which legal grounds they are using your data","correct":false},{"text":"They must use and process the data fairly with your interest in mind","correct":false},{"text":"They must inform you how they will use your information","correct":false},{"text":"All of the above","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"GDPR says that businesses must only use your information for the purposes you have agreed to, which GDPR priciple does that relate to?","postQuestionText":"Purpose limitation states that information should be obtained only for \u0022specified, explicit and legitimate purposes\u0022","answers":[{"text":"Storage limitation","correct":false},{"text":"Integrity and confidentiality","correct":false},{"text":"Accuracy","correct":false},{"text":"Purpose limitation","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"GDPR talks about \u0022data minimisation\u0022, what does this mean?","postQuestionText":"Collecting the minimum amount of data required and using that data only in a way that has been agreed","answers":[{"text":"Reducing the font size","correct":false},{"text":"Telling me as little as possible","correct":false},{"text":"Only collecting what they need","correct":true},{"text":"Having a small database","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"How can you check your social media privacy settings work?","postQuestionText":"Log out or go onto another device and search for you on google or social media","answers":[{"text":"Go onto another device and look at your social media from there","correct":true},{"text":"Hope for the best","correct":false},{"text":"You can\u0027t","correct":false},{"text":"Ask a friend","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"True or false: you will always know straight away if a virus is on your computer.","postQuestionText":"No, it is not always easy to determine if your computer has been affected by a virus","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"What is malware?","postQuestionText":"Malicious Software. Malware is a generic term for software designed to install, spread, and execute malicious code on a device, network or service.","answers":[{"text":"Bad data","correct":false},{"text":"Malicious Software","correct":true},{"text":"Sneaky files","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What is phishing?","postQuestionText":"A disguised message that appears to be from a genuine source designed to trick the recipient into opening malicious links.","answers":[{"text":"Using a rod and line to catch fish","correct":false},{"text":"Hooking new friends online by circulating exciting news","correct":false},{"text":"A malicious message disguised to appear genuine","correct":true},{"text":"A funny email to attract more followers","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What is a \u0027man in the middle\u0027 attack?","postQuestionText":"A secret eavesdropping attack","answers":[{"text":"A man squashed too tightly in between two others","correct":false},{"text":"A computer inserted between two networks","correct":false},{"text":"A malicious attacker","correct":false},{"text":"A secret eavesdropping attack","correct":true}]}]},{"name":"Relationships","questions":[{"questionText":"True or false: It is easy to identify someone with genuine intention on the internet.","postQuestionText":"It is not always easy to identify someone with genuine intentions on the internet. People who do not have genuine intentions will try hard to appear genuine.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Someone that you have known online for a while wants to meet you outside the local shops, so you can hang out. What should you do?","postQuestionText":"If you do go and meet them, get permission and take an adult with you.","answers":[{"text":"If you have known them for a long time and you trust them, you can go and meet them alone","correct":false},{"text":"If you do go and meet them, get permission and take an adult with you","correct":true},{"text":"You should never go and meet anyone that you have met online under any circumstances","correct":false},{"text":"Make sure your friends know when and where you are meeting them","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Your online gaming accounts are private and you have fewer friends online than you do in real life. What do you do?","postQuestionText":"Keep your accounts private and never add strangers as friends.","answers":[{"text":"Add every account you can find","correct":false},{"text":"Put a notice on each of your accounts for people to add you","correct":false},{"text":"Delete your accounts so as not to be embarrassed","correct":false},{"text":"Keep your accounts private and never add strangers as friends","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Someone you have known online for a long time wants to meet in real life. Is it ok for me to go and meet them alone?","postQuestionText":"No - never meet up with people you don\u0027t know in real life alone; make sure you have an adult/parent or guardian with you, you meet in a public place and other people know where you are.","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":false},{"text":"No","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"What is radicalisation?","postQuestionText":"Radicalisation is a process by which individuals, often young people, are maipuated into supporting extreme ideological views. This is increasingly taking place through social media.","answers":[{"text":"A manipulation technique used by extremists","correct":true},{"text":"A manipulation technique used by friends","correct":false},{"text":"A method of growing radishes quickly","correct":false},{"text":"A radical change of pace","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Is sexting legal for those under 18 years of age?","postQuestionText":"No, the law says that creating or sharing sexual images or videos of a child under 18 is illegal, even if the person doing it is a child","answers":[{"text":"Yes, as long as you hide your face","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, as long as you don\u2019t share your name","correct":false},{"text":"No, the law says that creating or sharing sexual images or videos of a child under 18 is illegal, even if the person doing it is a child","correct":true},{"text":"Yes, as long as you are both under 18","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What should someone who is under 18 do if someone they don\u0027t know communicates with them online about wanting to sext with them?","postQuestionText":"It is illegal for anyone to exchange sexual images with a person under the age of 18, even if they are under 18 themselves. Always report such activity: you can report to the social media platform and to a Child Protection Advisor at the Child Exploitation Online Protection team.","answers":[{"text":"Nothing","correct":false},{"text":"Giggle with their friends about it","correct":false},{"text":"Respond to them with a picture of yourself","correct":false},{"text":"Do not respond and always report","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"Should you accept a friend request from a friend that you met through work?","postQuestionText":"Yes, you can accept a friend request from a colleague, however never feel that you must. You should also think about what content is available for them to see on your account.","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":true},{"text":"No","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Is it appropriate to upload a picture of you and a friend without asking them first?","postQuestionText":"No, it is always best to check with them first. You should never share pictures of anyone else without asking for their permission.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, they won\u0027t mind if it is a nice picture","correct":false},{"text":"It is my picture so I can upload it if I want to","correct":false},{"text":"No, never upload pictures of anybody but yourself","correct":false},{"text":"No, it is always best to check with them first","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"How can you find out how old someone you are talking to online is?","postQuestionText":"You can\u2019t, they may have lied or they could be imitating somebody else","answers":[{"text":"Check their other online profiles","correct":false},{"text":"Do a reverse image search to see if you can find them","correct":false},{"text":"Ask them","correct":false},{"text":"You can\u2019t","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"What is sexting?","postQuestionText":"Sexting or sending nudes is when someone shares a sexual message, naked or semi-naked image, video or text message with another person; it doesn\u2019t have to be a nude image of them and could be an image of someone else.","answers":[{"text":"Watching porn on a mobile device","correct":false},{"text":"Sharing a link to a porn site to your social media","correct":false},{"text":"Sharing a sexual text, image or video with another person","correct":true},{"text":"Writing a explicit fanfiction","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What are the risks of sexting?","postQuestionText":"There are many risks that could come from sexting. You could lose control of the images, videos or messages and how they\u0027re shared and they could be used for revenge porn or blackmail. Sharing sexual images of under 18s is always child pornography and sharing sexual images of somebody without their consent is always illegal.","answers":[{"text":"There are none, it\u0027s just a bit of fun","correct":false},{"text":"My partner might show them to his friends","correct":false},{"text":"None, if I trust my partner","correct":false},{"text":"You could lose control of the content","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"In 2019, Twitter announced they would delete accounts that had been inactive for 6 months. This prompted outrage from people who wanted to keep their deceased loved ones memories and tweets alive. Did they go ahead with this?","postQuestionText":"No, Twitter tweeted that they wouldn\u0027t remove any accounts until it could offer a way to keep those that belong to people who have passed away","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":false},{"text":"No","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"You are out with friends and one of them sprays graffiti on the street - you film the act, upload it on social media and everyone shares the video. Is this acceptable?","postQuestionText":"No, filming someone spray painting graffiti may seem cool but it\u0027s actually evidence of a crime and could be used against them.","answers":[{"text":"Yes","correct":false},{"text":"No","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"What proportion of 17 year olds admitted sending a sext to another person?","postQuestionText":"20% or 1 in 5 17 year olds have sent a sext. Remember, sharing sexual images or videos of under 18s is always illegal (even if the sharer is under 18).","answers":[{"text":"1 in 100","correct":false},{"text":"1 in 50","correct":false},{"text":"1 in 25","correct":false},{"text":"1 in 5","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"I can edit my online identity at any point and I will be able to delete old posts from my past.","postQuestionText":"False. Posting is permanent. Many people think that deleting something online means removing it from the internet forever. This is not true. After posting something online, anyone can save, download and re-use it! Just think about all the recent scandals around the uncovering of old, inappropriate tweets by a host of now infamous celebrities!","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":false},{"text":"False","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"How do you know that a friend request on your social media account is really coming from your friend?","postQuestionText":"Where possible, check with your friends in real life that the account is theirs.","answers":[{"text":"We have mutual friends","correct":false},{"text":"It has pictures of them on the account","correct":false},{"text":"You can never be sure, check with your friend in real life","correct":true},{"text":"It has correct personal details on the account","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What does it mean for a social media account to be \u0027verified\u0027?","postQuestionText":"Verified badges help people to more easily find genuine public figures or celebrities online. Be suspicious if somebody contacts you online claiming to be a celebrity when they do not have a badge to say that they have been verified.","answers":[{"text":"That an account has been confirmed as genuine by the platform","correct":true},{"text":"That the username exists","correct":false},{"text":"That the user gets paid by the platform","correct":false},{"text":"The user has more than 50,000 followers","correct":false}]}]},{"name":"Wellbeing","questions":[{"questionText":"What is the best way to know whether a video game is suitable for a young person?","postQuestionText":"PEGI (Pan European Game Information) is an official association design to look into the games and give indication of which age group the game is suitable for.","answers":[{"text":"Check online for other people opinions","correct":false},{"text":"Play the game first to understand if you are ok with its content","correct":false},{"text":"Check what rating was given by PEGI","correct":true},{"text":"All of the above","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"If a game is marked by PEGI as 3\u002B (safe for everyone), does this mean that children do not need supervision while playing?","postQuestionText":"No, PEGI does not consider chat or in-app purchase features. This puts children at risk of exposure to strangers or purchasing items without being fully aware of spending real money.","answers":[{"text":"Yes, anyone can play it and it is completely safe","correct":false},{"text":"No, there are game features not considered by PEGI","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"What is livestreaming?","postQuestionText":"Livestreaming is broadcasting to an audience in real time. The audience can often leave comments or give likes to the person streaming. Some platforms let several people livestream at the same time. There are livestreaming apps like Twitch, Youtube and Yubo, but you can livestream on other social media platforms, including Facebook and Instagram.","answers":[{"text":"Running down a stream and feeling alive","correct":false},{"text":"Listening to music on Spotify","correct":false},{"text":"Watching illegal content online","correct":false},{"text":"Broadcasting to an online audience in real time","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"What is a deepfake?","postQuestionText":"Deepfakes are false images or videos created using AI to create realistic-looking content. These are often presented as real and can be used to decieve others.","answers":[{"text":"Deepfakes are false images or videos created using AI to create realistic-looking content","correct":true},{"text":"A person who is very insincere","correct":false},{"text":"When influencers do not declare that a post is sponsored","correct":false},{"text":"When someone heavily filters or edits their photos without declaring it","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Electronically altering a video by swapping your voice or face with someone else and passing this off as real is known as?","postQuestionText":"A deepfake","answers":[{"text":"Digital enhancement","correct":false},{"text":"Artistic license","correct":false},{"text":"A deepfake","correct":true},{"text":"All of the above","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Which of these types of images is it appropriate to share on your social media site?","postQuestionText":"It is okay to upload a picture of yourself but you always need to get permission to upload pictures of other people. It is important to think about the consequences of what you are sharing online.","answers":[{"text":"A picture of yourself","correct":true},{"text":"A picture of your friends doing something they should not be doing","correct":false},{"text":"An embarrassing picture of your friend","correct":false},{"text":"Explicit or provocative image of a friend or partner","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"A friend uploads an unflattering, explicit or unkind image of you to their social media site and shares this with their friends, what should you do?","postQuestionText":"Before you upload photos to social media, you need to consider the consequences of your actions. Photos that you think are funny now, might later damage their reputation and it could even lose them job opportunities.","answers":[{"text":"Speak to your friend and ask them to remove the image, report them if they don\u0027t","correct":true},{"text":"Retaliate by posting a funny or unkind picture of your friend in response","correct":false},{"text":"Unfriend them and ask all of your friends to do the same","correct":false},{"text":"Nothing, it is just a bit of fun","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"True or false: you can you be addicted to social media.","postQuestionText":"This is true. If your social media is negatively impacting on other areas of your life, such as your mood, your sleep or your relationships with others, then you should ask for help.","answers":[{"text":"True","correct":true},{"text":"False","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What is a social media influencer?","postQuestionText":"Someone with an account on an online platform who has a large number of followers. They tend to recommend products to buy (often with sponsorship from the company) and promote their lifestyle","answers":[{"text":"Friends who try to get me to post videos on TikTok, even when I do not want to","correct":false},{"text":"Tech CEOs eg Mark Zuckerberg or Bill Gates","correct":false},{"text":"Someone who has influence over social media policy","correct":false},{"text":"Someone with a large number of online followers, who tend to promote product associated with their lifestyle","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"What can I do when social media feels like it is getting too much?","postQuestionText":"Take some time away, connect with people in real life and when you return, try to find some positive social media influences.","answers":[{"text":"Share my feelings with others on Social Media","correct":false},{"text":"Delete all of my online accounts permanently","correct":false},{"text":"Take some time away and/or connect with people in real life","correct":true},{"text":"Wait for it to pass","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"If someone creates a social-networking page (such as on Facebook) impersonating you, you should:","postQuestionText":"Report the page, make others aware and contact the site administrator","answers":[{"text":"Report the page, make others aware and contact the site adminstrator","correct":true},{"text":"Ignore it and it will go away","correct":false},{"text":"Get revenge by creating an account impersonating them","correct":false},{"text":"Join the page to try and find out who created the account","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"If you are playing an online game, you may be asked to make an in-game purchase. What is this? ","postQuestionText":"A fee to purchase in-game currency or items. Even though some games are free to download, they may ask players to buy credits or items so they can keep playing or enhace the gaming experience. These costs can built up.","answers":[{"text":"An online grocery order","correct":false},{"text":"When you purchase a game on Amazon","correct":false},{"text":"A purchase using a digital currency","correct":false},{"text":"A real cost to purchase in-game currency or items","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"What could be an effect of catfishing someone?","postQuestionText":"All of the above","answers":[{"text":"Damage to mental health","correct":false},{"text":"Embarrassment for falling for the catfish","correct":false},{"text":"Longterm problems with anxiety and depression","correct":false},{"text":"All of the above","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"How can you recognise if a website is safe?","postQuestionText":"On the left side of the URL bar, there should be a little padlock which is showing that you should be on a secure site","answers":[{"text":"It looks professional","correct":false},{"text":"There is a little padlock at the left of the URL bar","correct":true},{"text":"A friend told you it\u0027s safe","correct":false},{"text":"I would follow my intuition","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Does privacy mean the same to everyone?","postQuestionText":"Privacy is subjective, which means it depends on your views, values and experiences. For example, would you consider it a violation of your privacy if someone shared a photo of you without you agreeing to it?","answers":[{"text":"Yes, everyone will feel the same","correct":false},{"text":"No, everyone will feel different","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"What is a money mule or smurfer?","postQuestionText":"A money mule is a person who transfers money acquired illegally on behalf of others. Money mules are often recruited on-line for what they think is legitimate employment, not aware that the money they are transferring is the product of crime.","answers":[{"text":"A small donkey used to transport money","correct":false},{"text":"Someone whose bank account is used to move money for criminal activities","correct":true},{"text":"Someone who sends money electonically to other people","correct":false},{"text":"Someone who works hard for very little money","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"What is ghosting?","postQuestionText":"Ghosting is abruptly ending communication with someone without explanation. The concept most often refers to romantic relationships but can also describe disappearances from friendships and the workplace.","answers":[{"text":"A type of hacking","correct":false},{"text":"A form of online trolling","correct":false},{"text":"Abruptly ending communication with someone","correct":true},{"text":"A way scare someone","correct":false}]},{"questionText":"Do you still need to worry about identity theft if you have no money in the bank?","postQuestionText":"Cybercriminals sometimes target teen\u2019s blank slate of credit and open up accounts that can follow you for years to come. The damage can impact your future by making it harder to do things like buy a car, travel or get a job.","answers":[{"text":"No, it is not a problem","correct":false},{"text":"Only if I plan to borrow money in the near future","correct":false},{"text":"Only if it\u0027s linked to my phone","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, it is still a concern","correct":true}]},{"questionText":"When might be a bad time to share something online?","postQuestionText":"If you are feeling upset or angry, it may be a bad time to be messaging or posting on social media because people don\u0027t always make good decisions when they\u0027re stressed or upset. You could call someone or get some fresh air instead.","answers":[{"text":"When you are feeling unwell","correct":false},{"text":"When you are feeling upset or angry","correct":true},{"text":"When you are feeling really excited","correct":false},{"text":"When you are feeling tired","correct":false}]}]}]}